<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Admissions &#8211; RW TC</title>
	<atom:link href="https://rw.tc.columbia.edu/category/admissions/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://rw.tc.columbia.edu</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 02:22:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Attracting the best minds in pursuit of greater human understanding, pioneering new discoveries, and service to society.</title>
		<link>https://rw.tc.columbia.edu/attracting-the-best-minds-in-pursuit-of-greater-human-understanding-pioneering-new-discoveries-and-service-to-society/</link>
					<comments>https://rw.tc.columbia.edu/attracting-the-best-minds-in-pursuit-of-greater-human-understanding-pioneering-new-discoveries-and-service-to-society/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[paglaadmin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 02:22:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Admissions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://rw.tc.columbia.edu/?p=27</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For more than 250 years, Columbia has been a leader in higher education in the nation and around the world. At the core of our wide range of academic inquiry is the commitment to attract and engage the best minds in pursuit of greater human understanding, pioneering new discoveries, and service to society. Visit Contact...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For more than 250 years, Columbia has been a leader in higher education in the nation and around the world. At the core of our wide range of academic inquiry is the commitment to attract and engage the best minds in pursuit of greater human understanding, pioneering new discoveries, and service to society.</p>
<p><strong>Visit</strong></p>
<p>Contact the Visitors Center to schedule a tour of the Morningside campus.</p>
<p><strong>Learn</strong></p>
<p>Learn more about being a part of the Columbia community while living in one of the world’s great cities.</p>
<p><strong>Apply</strong></p>
<p>A list of the admissions sites for each of Columbia&#8217;s schools</p>
<p><strong>EXPLORE</strong></p>
<p>Columbia offers a comprehensive array of academic programs. These include three undergraduate schools, fourteen graduate and professional schools, a world-renowned medical center, four affiliated colleges and seminaries, twenty-six libraries, and nearly two hundred research centers and institutes.</p>
<p><strong>Academic Calendar</strong></p>
<p>Find important academic dates and deadlines.</p>
<p><strong>Areas of Study</strong></p>
<p>Looking for info on a specific area of study? Search by keyword or view an alphabetical list.</p>
<p><strong>International Students &amp; Scholars Office</strong></p>
<p>International students who have been admitted to a full-time program will apply here for visa documents.</p>
<p><strong>Schools</strong></p>
<p>Read specific information on admission to a particular Columbia school.</p>
<p><strong>Departments</strong></p>
<p>Search for a specific department or see a list of all departments.</p>
<p><strong>Courses</strong></p>
<p>Peruse the extensive list of courses offered at Columbia.</p>
<p><strong>Financial Aid</strong></p>
<p>Review a start-up guide to financial aid and learn more about how to apply.</p>
<p><strong>Centers and Institutes</strong></p>
<p>Search Columbia&#8217;s broad spectrum of research institutes and centers.</p>
<p><strong>University Life</strong></p>
<p>Your hub for University-wide student life information and initiatives.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://rw.tc.columbia.edu/attracting-the-best-minds-in-pursuit-of-greater-human-understanding-pioneering-new-discoveries-and-service-to-society/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
