<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>News &#8211; RW TC</title>
	<atom:link href="https://rw.tc.columbia.edu/category/news/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://rw.tc.columbia.edu</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 02:11:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>An Expansive View Into Obama’s Transformative Presidency</title>
		<link>https://rw.tc.columbia.edu/an-expansive-view-into-obamas-transformative-presidency/</link>
					<comments>https://rw.tc.columbia.edu/an-expansive-view-into-obamas-transformative-presidency/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[paglaadmin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 02:11:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://rw.tc.columbia.edu/?p=13</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The first set of transcripts from the Obama Presidency Oral History will be released today. “How will Obama’s Presidency be remembered? A massive new oral history project will help shape his legacy,” read the headline in The Washington Post on May 16, 2019. The article announced how a team of sociologists and oral historians from...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The first set of transcripts from the Obama Presidency Oral History will be released today.</p>
<p>“How will Obama’s Presidency be remembered? A massive new oral history project will help shape his legacy,” read the headline in The Washington Post on May 16, 2019. The article announced how a team of sociologists and oral historians from Columbia University’s Incite and Columbia Center for Oral History Research (CCOHR) were chosen by the Obama Foundation to document President Obama’s time in the Oval Office. To accurately reflect the transformative nature of this presidency, the team set out to create a presidential oral history like no other.</p>
<p>Just over four years later, 470 people have been interviewed with roughly 1,100 hours of video and audio recordings, much of it produced during the COVID-19 pandemic. And now, the team is ready to publish the first set of their interviews on the topic of climate change. What sets this project apart from other presidential oral histories? Columbia News talked to the leadership team to find out.</p>
<p>The Team<br />
The principal investigator on the Obama Presidency Oral History is Peter Bearman, Jonathan R. Cole Professor of Sociology and director of Incite. Mary Marshall Clark, director of CCHOR, and Kimberly Springer, curator of the Oral History Archives at Columbia University Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library, were co-investigators. All three have decades of expertise in the field of oral history.</p>
<p>Bearman and Michael Falco, executive director of Incite, found three accomplished historians—Dov Weinryb Grohsgal, Nicole Hemmer, and Evan McCormick—to lead the research. Grohsgal was a dean at Princeton University and had done research into key moments of the Obama presidency, like Obamacare and the fiscal crisis. When Hemmer joined, she was at the Miller Center, a nonpartisan affiliate of the University of Virginia that specializes in presidential scholarship, public policy, and political history, where she focused on the media, conservatism, and the far-right. McCormick specialized in foreign policy issues, inter-American relations during the Reagan years, and contested ideas of security, democracy, and rights in the Western Hemisphere. He brought a global focus to the project.</p>
<p>Next to join the team was Terrell Frazier, an experienced oral historian and sociologist. Back in 2019, he was working on his sociology Ph.D. at Columbia when Bearman tapped him to be the lead interviewer for the project. Frazier’s research investigated the relationship between social movement actors’ social positions and their capacities for strategic action.</p>
<p>Along with this team and dozens of other staffers, students, and interviewers, the project was guided by the Obama Presidency Oral History’s advisory board that consisted of prominent historians, journalists, sociologists, and lawyers. “The board has been influential in driving some innovations in this project,” remarked Bearman. “We’ve been able to take the board’s guidance and broaden the frame quite remarkably.”</p>
<p>On the archival side of the project, Chelsea Reil, joined Columbia University Libraries in 2022 as the person responsible for describing the collection and stewarding the project through the cataloging process.</p>
<p>The Project&#8217;s Design<br />
A typical presidential oral history focuses on the president and a small group of advisers around him. Bearman and his team, however, wanted this project to reflect Obama’s approach to the presidency, one where he aspired to be in touch with the American people. “We wanted to decenter the presidency,” said Bearman. “We explored the relationship between those who have power and those who are recipients of that power. But we also examined how the experiences of those ‘ordinary’ people percolated back into the policies of the administration.”</p>
<p>To provide a full picture of Obama’s impact, the team identified nearly 40 policy topics, including healthcare, Black politics, climate change, the environment, and energy. The research process then revealed a variety of people to possibly interview: not just high-level administration figures, but also mid-level staffers, activists, people affected by the policy, and also those who affected or shaped policy, like elected officials, university presidents, and people of every walk of life.</p>
<p>Presidential oral histories often have a very small number of interviews devoted to first ladies and how they operate outside of the West Wing. The team took a different approach with a significant focus on the office and included more than 30 interview participants. “I didn’t try to compare First Lady Michelle Obama to other first ladies,” said Clark, who conducted dozens of East Wing interviews. “I focused more on the productiveness of her and her husband’s work together.”</p>
<p>The Interview Process and COVID&#8217;s Impact<br />
The Columbia Center for Oral History Research is the oldest and one of the largest oral history centers in the country. Clark and Frazier utilized some of the interviews from the center’s vast oral history collections, including the September 11, 2001 Oral History Project and the Guantanamo Bay Oral History Project, to help train the interviewers in the project’s opening phase.</p>
<p>Each interviewer spent significant time engaging with the narrators prior to the interviews. Additionally, an enormous amount of research was distilled into specific topical outlines that each interviewee would receive prior to the interview. Initially, the interviews were scheduled to be in person. However, only a few were completed when the COVID-pandemic hit, and the team needed to shift gears to remote interviews.</p>
<p>“Like all oral histories, they’re shaped by the moment in which they are collected,” remarked Bearman. “Today, plague and loneliness and isolation are not the first things that come to mind when we think about the world. But in 2020 and 2021, they were powerful frames for people, and we were able to think deeply with our narrators about what the world was like in a period just before this unusual moment in time.”</p>
<p>How to Access the Interviews<br />
The public will be able to access the interviews in several ways. Incite will launch a preview version of the project’s website on May 31. The first tranche of interviews available will focus on President Obama’s work on climate change. More sets of interviews will be released throughout the year and into 2024.</p>
<p>“The website will allow individuals to watch the video we captured, listen to the audio, and to read the transcripts,” explained Bearman. “We hope the site will reveal the ways in which issues relate to each other and the feel of the presidency.”</p>
<p>The interviews will also be made available for use by the Obama Foundation and the Obama Presidential Center, which is under construction in Chicago’s South Side. The archive will be housed and preserved at Columbia University Libraries&#8217; Rare Book &amp; Manuscript Library. Incite also commissioned interviews with partners at the University of Hawaii and the University of Chicago that focused on President Obama and the First Lady’s earlier lives and careers. These subsections of the project will be housed at both Universities.</p>
<p>When asked what she hopes people will learn from the archive now and in the future, Reil responded, “I hope they learn the power of people&#8217;s personal stories and experiences when taking a wide view of history.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://rw.tc.columbia.edu/an-expansive-view-into-obamas-transformative-presidency/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lenfest Distinguished Faculty Awardees, American Philosophical Society Members, and More</title>
		<link>https://rw.tc.columbia.edu/lenfest-distinguished-faculty-awardees-american-philosophical-society-members-and-more/</link>
					<comments>https://rw.tc.columbia.edu/lenfest-distinguished-faculty-awardees-american-philosophical-society-members-and-more/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[paglaadmin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 02:09:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://rw.tc.columbia.edu/?p=9</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[From science to engineering, writing to social sciences, here are the Columbians who received awards recently. Columbia News produces a biweekly newsletter (subscribe here!) and article series featuring a roundup of awards and milestones that Columbia faculty, staff, and students have received in recent days. In this edition, you’ll find awards and milestones from May...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>From science to engineering, writing to social sciences, here are the Columbians who received awards recently.</p>
<p>Columbia News produces a biweekly newsletter (subscribe here!) and article series featuring a roundup of awards and milestones that Columbia faculty, staff, and students have received in recent days. In this edition, you’ll find awards and milestones from May 18 to June 1, 2023.</p>
<p>Have an award or milestone you’d like to have featured in the newsletter or article online? Please send an email to newsteam@columbia.edu. Note that we’ll be running this series every other week.</p>
<p>You can take a look at past accomplishments on our Awards &amp; Milestones page. And you can subscribe to receive the newsletter in your inbox.</p>
<p>FACULTY<br />
Eight faculty members were named Lenfest Distinguished Faculty Awardees for 2022-2023.</p>
<p>ARTS &amp; HUMANITIES<br />
Camila Marie Agosto, DMA student in composition in the Music Department; Michael Doyle, University Professor at SIPA; Liana Finck, adjunct assistant professor in the English Department at Barnard; Heidi Julavits, writing professor at School of the Arts; James Shapiro, Larry Miller Professor of English and Comparative Literature; and Mabel O. Wilson, Nancy and George Rupp Professor of Architecture, Planning and Preservation, have all been named 2023-2024 Berlin Prize Fellows.</p>
<p>Antoine Marcel Compagnon, Blanche W. Knopf Professor of French and Comparative Literature, was recently installed as an honorary member of the Japan Academy and a member of the Académie Française.</p>
<p>Kellie Jones, Hans Hofmann Professor of Modern Art and chair of the Department of African American and African Diaspora Studies, and Bruce Western, Bryce Professor of Sociology and Social Justice and director of the Justice Lab, have been named 2023 members of the American Philosophical Society.</p>
<p>SCIENCE &amp; MEDICINE<br />
Eddy Albarran, Floor Broekgaarden, Juan Esteban Rodríguez Camargo, and Isabel Low have been named 2023 Junior Fellows in the Simons Society of Fellows. The fellows, outstanding early-career scientists, and mathematicians based in the New York City area, receive support from the Simons Foundation for up to three years of independent research with no teaching obligations.</p>
<p>Andrea Califano, Clyde &#8217;56 and Helen Wu Professor of Chemical Biology (in Systems Biology), was awarded $6,909,000 over seven years from the National Cancer Institute for &#8220;Cancer Cell Response to Endogenous and Exogenous Perturbations at the Single Cell Level.&#8221;</p>
<p>The College of Dental Medicine Epsilon Epsilon chapter of Omicron Kappa Upsilon, the national dental honor society, inducted 11 students and three faculty members. The student inductees were Anamaria Carrasco, Jessica Castillo, Renee Eisenberg, Navreet Kaur, Simon Luu, Maura Lynch, Charlotte Martin, Margot Metz, Yvonne O’Neal, Nolan Wendling, and Zeming Zheng. Faculty inductees were Mona Boside, assistant professor of Dental Medicine; Alison Newgard, assistant professor of Dental Medicine; and honorary inductee Carol Kunzel, professor of Dental Community Health.</p>
<p>Elizabeth Corwin, Anna C. Maxwell Professor of Nursing Research, Stephen Ferrara, associate professor of Nursing, Vivian Taylor, associate dean for Diversity and Cultural Affairs, and Julia Iyasere, assistant professor of Clinical Medicine, were selected as Notable 2023 Leaders in Health Care by Crain’s New York Business.</p>
<p>Joel Gabre, assistant professor of Medicine, has received the American Gastroenterological Association Research Scholar Award.</p>
<p>Madelyn S. Gould, Irving Philips Professor of Epidemiology, received a Lifetime Achievement Research Award from the American Foundation for Suicide Prevention at the foundation&#8217;s Lifesavers Gala on May 4.</p>
<p>Dawn L. Hershman, professor of Medicine and Epidemiology, has been selected as a co-chair-elect of the SWOG Cancer Research Network.</p>
<p>Ben Izar, assistant professor of Medicine and Systems Biology, has been awarded the 2023 Pershing Square Sohn Prize for Young Investigators in Cancer Research.</p>
<p>Ryan Lawrence, associate professor of psychiatry, and Mark Sorensen, associate clinical professor of psychiatry, are recipients of the 2022-2023 Irma Bland Award for Excellence in Teaching Residents from the American Psychiatric Association (APA). The award recognizes APA members who have made outstanding and sustaining contributions to resident education in psychiatry. Sorensen passed away earlier this year and was granted the award posthumously.</p>
<p>Stephen Novak, head of Archives &amp; Special Collections at the Augustus C. Long Health Sciences Library at the Medical Center, was awarded the 2023 “Best Monograph” prize by the Librarians, Archivists, and Museum Professionals in the History of the Health Sciences for a book, &#8220;The Babies Hospital of New York: A History,&#8221; co-written with Michael Weiner, special lecturer in the Department of Pediatrics.</p>
<p>Marcel F. Nutz, professor of Statistics, has been named Fellow of the Institute of Mathematical Statistics. Nutz received the award for outstanding contributions to probability, in particular to optimal transport, stochastic analysis, and mathematical finance, and for dedicated service to the profession.</p>
<p>Anil Rustgi, director of the Herbert Irving Comprehensive Cancer Center, has received the William Beaumont Prize in Gastroenterology from the American Gastroenterological Association.</p>
<p>Tim Wang, chief of the Division of Digestive and Liver Diseases, has received the American Gastroenterological Association Friedenwald Medal.</p>
<p>ENGINEERING<br />
Nadeen Chahine, associate professor of Biomechanics (in Orthopaedic Surgery), and Lance Kam, professor of Biomedical Engineering, have been elected as fellows of the American Institute for Medical and Biological Engineering College of Fellows.</p>
<p>George Deodatis, Santiago and Robertina Calatrava Family Professor of Civil Engineering, and Feniosky Peña-Mora, Edwin Howard Armstrong Professor of Civil Engineering and Engineering Mechanics, have been named Distinguished Members of the American Society of Civil Engineers (ASCE), the highest honor awarded to ASCE members who have made substantial contributions to the profession through their research, publications, and service to the industry.</p>
<p>Helen Lu, Percy K. and Vida L.W. Hudson Professor of Biomedical Engineering and senior vice dean of Faculty Affairs and Advancement, has been awarded the ELLE &amp; Polestar Design Towards Zero Award for the company she co-founded, Werewool.</p>
<p>Stavros Thomopoulos, Robert E. Carroll and Jane Chace Carroll Laboratories Professor of Orthopaedic Surgery, has been elected Conference Chair of the Summer Biomechanics, Bioengineering, and Biotransport Conference (2023) by the SB3C Foundation.</p>
<p>Gordana Vunjak-Novakovic, University Professor and Mikati Foundation Professor of Biomedical Engineering, was elected Chair of the Bioengineering Section of the National Academy of Engineering. Vunjak-Novakovic was also recognized in the Top 50 Academic Life Science Entrepreneurs by BIOS and won the Annual award for the best paper by a woman in science by the Mary Ann Liebert Inc. and Rosalind Franklin Society.</p>
<p>Steve WaiChing Sun, associate professor of civil engineering and engineering mechanics at Columbia Engineering, has been awarded the 2023 Walter L. Huber Civil Engineering Research Prize of the American Society of Civil Engineers. Cited for his “fundamental contributions to computational and data-driven poromechanics,” Sun is an expert who synthesizes physical insight, machine learning, and advanced mathematical methods with wide application in engineering analysis.</p>
<p>Bolun Xu, assistant professor of earth and environmental engineering, received an NSF CAREER Award for his proposal, “Computation-efficient Algorithms for Grid-scale Energy Storage Control, Bidding, and Integration Analysis.” The award supports early-career faculty who have the potential to serve as academic role models in research and education and to lead advances in the mission of their department or organization.</p>
<p>Moti Yung, adjunct senior research scientist in the Department of Computer Science and a 1988 PhD graduate of computer science, has been elected to the American Academy of Arts and Sciences.</p>
<p>STUDENTS<br />
Hailey Arango (GSAS’23) was given the inaugural Department of Ecology, Evolution and Environmental Biology (E3B) MA Thesis Award. The award was established in honor of the late Eleanor J. Sterling, who passed away this year. The award is in acknowledgement of Sterling’s tireless efforts to advance conservation through teaching and mentoring, research, on-the-ground conservation, public outreach, and policy. The award will be given annually to an MA student whose thesis reflects the major thrusts of Sterling’s mentoring, research, community based conservation, and systems thinking.</p>
<p>Amelia Chambliss, Jacob Halpern, and Pavan Ravindra have been named Department of Energy Computational Science Graduate Fellows (DOE CSGF). The program, established in 1991 and jointly funded by the DOE Office of Science and National Nuclear Security Administration (NNSA), trains top leaders in computational science.</p>
<p>Victoria O. Nguyen, Ph.D. student studying child and adolescent mental health disparities at the School of Social Work, was announced by the Society for Research in Child Development (SRCD) as a Horowitz Early Career Scholar for 2023. This prestigious national award recognizes promising early career scholars in the field of developmental sciences.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://rw.tc.columbia.edu/lenfest-distinguished-faculty-awardees-american-philosophical-society-members-and-more/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Debt Ceiling Deal and Its Economic Fallout</title>
		<link>https://rw.tc.columbia.edu/the-debt-ceiling-deal-and-its-economic-fallout/</link>
					<comments>https://rw.tc.columbia.edu/the-debt-ceiling-deal-and-its-economic-fallout/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[paglaadmin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 02:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://rw.tc.columbia.edu/?p=6</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Senate finally approved the bipartisan debt limit bill, averting a debt default. But, what price will the U.S. pay for this latest game of brinkmanship? A quirky feature of the American political system is that the amount of debt that the U.S. Treasury is allowed to issue is capped by Congress (currently) at $31.4...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Senate finally approved the bipartisan debt limit bill, averting a debt default. But, what price will the U.S. pay for this latest game of brinkmanship?</p>
<p>A quirky feature of the American political system is that the amount of debt that the U.S. Treasury is allowed to issue is capped by Congress (currently) at $31.4 trillion, a number known as the debt ceiling. Since the amount of U.S. debt now roughly equals the debt ceiling, and because our government operates with a budget deficit, to fund ongoing operations—things like paying back existing debts, or paying government contractors and employees, or sending out Social Security checks—Congress needs to either raise or suspend the debt ceiling. It all sounds perfectly innocuous and wonky, but because the debt ceiling debate allows folks in Washington to advance party agendas, things sometimes get a bit out of hand. And that is what happened this time around.</p>
<p>Rather than doing what is obviously good for the country, the president and the Republican leadership in Congress engaged in a game of brinkmanship by, in effect, threatening to default on some (unspecified) set of U.S. government obligations unless one side gave in to the other’s political demands. After weeks of back and forth—with the commensurate, and often highly exaggerated, media forecasts of impending economic collapse should the debt ceiling not be raised by early June when the Treasury runs out of other funding sources—sanity finally prevailed with the House and Senate this week handily approving a bill that suspended the debt ceiling in return for cuts in federal spending.</p>
<p>Despite media prognostication, markets remained largely nonplussed with this week’s S&amp;P 500 rally as much due to strong economic data and excitement about AI, as to relief about a resolution to the debt ceiling debate. Given the relative brevity of this episode, there have been no obvious short-term economic impacts either.</p>
<p>No Harm, No Foul?<br />
The most lasting and damaging impact from the latest debt ceiling debacle is a slow erosion of confidence in the U.S. as a great place to do business. Because the dollar is the world’s reserve currency, the U.S. enjoys what economists call “exorbitant privilege,” which allows us to borrow voluminous amounts of money from the rest of the world at extremely attractive rates of interest. This state of affairs requires complete investor confidence that the U.S. is an attractive destination for their capital and that lending money to the U.S. government is one of the safest investments in the world.</p>
<p>The last time the U.S. was pushed to the brink of a potential default due to the debt ceiling debate, S&amp;P, one of the major rating agencies, cut our credit rating from AAA to AA+. This time around, Fitch, another of the major rating agencies, put its U.S. AAA rating on watch negative, meaning it may decide to downgrade the U.S. The games played in Washington have far reaching consequences for how the rest of the world perceives us. Unless we get our act together and implement a system that allows for a rational debate on government spending without the threat of a default on our government’s obligations, the patience of ratings agencies and of investors will grow thin. The consequences of that will be far reaching. Let’s hope we don’t find out what they are.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://rw.tc.columbia.edu/the-debt-ceiling-deal-and-its-economic-fallout/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
