<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Academics &#8211; RW TC</title>
	<atom:link href="https://rw.tc.columbia.edu/category/academics/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://rw.tc.columbia.edu</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 02:24:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Engaging the best minds in pursuit of greater human understanding, pioneering new discoveries, and service to society.</title>
		<link>https://rw.tc.columbia.edu/engaging-the-best-minds-in-pursuit-of-greater-human-understanding-pioneering-new-discoveries-and-service-to-society/</link>
					<comments>https://rw.tc.columbia.edu/engaging-the-best-minds-in-pursuit-of-greater-human-understanding-pioneering-new-discoveries-and-service-to-society/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[paglaadmin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 02:24:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Academics]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://rw.tc.columbia.edu/?p=30</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The University offers an outstanding and comprehensive array of academic programs. These include three undergraduate schools, thirteen graduate and professional schools, a world-renowned medical center, four affiliated colleges and seminaries, twenty-five libraries, and more than one hundred research centers and institutes. Schools For more information on one of Columbia&#8217;s undergraduate, graduate or professional schools Departments...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The University offers an outstanding and comprehensive array of academic programs. These include three undergraduate schools, thirteen graduate and professional schools, a world-renowned medical center, four affiliated colleges and seminaries, twenty-five libraries, and more than one hundred research centers and institutes.</p>
<p>Schools</p>
<p>For more information on one of Columbia&#8217;s undergraduate, graduate or professional schools</p>
<p>Departments</p>
<p>Search for a specific department at Columbia University or see a list of all departments.</p>
<p>Centers and Institutes</p>
<p>Search the broad spectrum of research institutes and centers in the natural and biomedical sciences, the social sciences and the humanities.</p>
<p>Areas of Study</p>
<p>Looking for information on a specific area of study? Search by keyword or view an alphabetical list.</p>
<p>Office of the Provost</p>
<p>The Office of the Provost maintains and advances the highest standards of scholarly research and teaching.</p>
<p>RESOURCES</p>
<p>Faculty of Arts and Sciences</p>
<p>The administrative body for faculty from the social sciences, humanities, and natural sciences.</p>
<p>Academic Calendar</p>
<p>Find important academic dates and deadlines.</p>
<p>Courseworks</p>
<p>Our learning management system offers a variety of online tools and features in support of teaching, learning and collaboration.</p>
<p>Directory of Classes</p>
<p>Search the extensive list of courses offered at Columbia.</p>
<p>Registrar</p>
<p>The Office of the Registrar directly supports scholarship, teaching, and learning.</p>
<p>High School Programs</p>
<p>Programs to engage and educate high school students.</p>
<p>Libraries</p>
<p>Access over 13 million volumes, 160,000 journals and serials, and extensive electronic resources.</p>
<p>University Life</p>
<p>Your hub for University-wide student life information and initiatives.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://rw.tc.columbia.edu/engaging-the-best-minds-in-pursuit-of-greater-human-understanding-pioneering-new-discoveries-and-service-to-society/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
